princetonreview.com 2005-04-03

# The Princeton Review

The Princeton Review takes your privacy seriously. This Privacy Policy applies to all of our customers, whether you buy our services or products online or offline. It also applies to visitors to our free websites.

The Princeton Review takes strong measures to protect your privacy. First, we only ask you to provide information that we need in order to deliver the service or information you have requested. Second, we don't share the information you have given us without your permission to do so. 

OVERALL

Services that Require Personal Information  
We will request personally identifiable information from you when you purchase some of our products, including online and offline courses, and when using some of our Web-based services. We will request information that we need in order for you to participate in the service (things like your name and address, for example) or pay for the service (credit card information, for example). Records of these transactions will be kept for customer service purposes only.

The Princeton Review offers several opportunities to receive products or information on- and off-line, either directly from us or from our partners. You indicate your wish to receive this information by checking a box on a form; unless you ask for it, nothing will be sent to you and nothing will be shared with third parties.

To fulfill your requests to receive information from us or others, we often need more information from you than when you only purchase a product or service from us. The additional information we ask for will vary depending on what it is you're requesting, but generally includes your mailing address, year of graduation, and other information that you choose to provide regarding your academic and extracurricular activities and interests. When you ask to receive information from or to be contacted by a third party, your information is passed on to the third party to fulfill your request; they may have their own privacy policies that differ from ours. The information we share may include any personally identifiable information we have about you, such as your name, address, academic record, and test scores.

We will not share your personally identifiable information with any third party, unless we need to in order to provide you the service you have purchased or you give us permission to share. We may track data on our customers in aggregate form. Such aggregated data does not uniquely identify you. We may share this aggregated data with others.

Schools  
We work with schools and institutions to provide programs such as test preparation and college counseling. Your school, district, or state may arrange for you to participate in these programs and may purchase products on your behalf. We may share personally identifiable information that you provide to us through your participation in these school programs with your school, district and your parents. In addition, your school may require us to share your information with others legally entitled to access your academic records, such as your state department of education.

COPPA Compliance  
The Princeton Review is in complete compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998. Except for K-12 students who participate in our Homeroom or ECOS product, we do not accept personally identifiable information online from children under the age of 13. (For more information on Homeroom or ECOS, please see below.) If we become aware that our records contain such information, we will delete it.

Marketing Lists  
From time to time, we obtain lists of people who may be interested in our products and services from third-party marketing list suppliers. We use these lists to send direct marketing promotions by mail or by email. We do our best to only obtain these lists from suppliers who have opt-in policies for third-party marketing, but we are not responsible for the conduct and policies of these suppliers. Please note that even if you are a registered customer of ours and have asked us not to use the information you provided to us to send you promotional material, a third-party marketing list supplier could still provide us with your name and address, in which case you will receive the promotional material sent by us to others on the supplier's list. If you have received a promotion from us and do not wish to receive future promotions, please contact us at: [privacy@review.com](mailto:privacy@review.com). 

LIVE COURSES

Subscriptions   
Many of our course students are given supplemental materials to help them prepare for their test. For example, if you become a student of The Princeton Review, we may provide you with magazine and/or newspaper subscriptions,* at no additional charge, as an additional benefit. If you would rather not receive supplemental materials, you will need to contact us and ask us to remove your name from our supplemental materials lists. Offline course students should contact your local office. Online students should email [support.online@mail.review.com](mailto:support.online@mail.review.com) or call 888.755.7737.

* For classes sold directly to students or their parents:  
_TIME_ : All SAT, ACT, GRE, GMAT, LSAT and MCAT classroom, tutoring and online course students for six months (students in school-based courses are not eligible for this offer)  
_The Wall Street Journal_ : All GMAT, GRE, MCAT and LSAT classroom, tutoring and online course students for one year

ON THE INTERNET

Anonymous Areas  
Some areas of our websites are accessible without registration of any kind. This is true of many of the basic content areas. Other areas require registration.

Services that Require Registration  
Some of our most useful services are personalized: different visitors get different results based on information they provide. Examples include but are not limited to Homeroom, Advanced School Search, Online Tests, Online Course Demos, School Match, the Tuition Cost Calculator, and any surveys or contests in which you may choose to participate. Registration for these services is required to facilitate customization of your individual results.

In addition to providing personalized results, registration is important for sending you specific information related to your service, and for allowing you to access stored information, and in the event that you opt-in, provide third party access to you. 

How are cookies used?  
We also use a software technology called "cookies" to create a personalized Web experience. Cookies cannot be used to find your name, email address, or anything that is uniquely identifying about you unless you provide that information. We use cookies for those applications to which we referred earlier that require us to keep track of information to customize results. If you don't have your browser set to accept cookies, certain areas of PrincetonReview.com, ECOS, and Homeroom.com will not function. We also allow you to choose to use a cookie to save your username and password so that you do not have to log in to the website each time you visit. We do not recommend this in multi-user environments such as school computer labs.

Partner Privacy Policies  
When you click on links and/or ad banners that take you to third-party websites, you will be subject to the third parties' privacy policies. While we support the protection of privacy on the Internet, The Princeton Review cannot be responsible for the actions of third parties. We encourage you to read the posted privacy statement whenever interacting with any website you visit. Homeroom.com and ECOS do not display third party banner ads on the site, although there may be resource links to third party content.

Passive Collection of Data  
Like most sites, we maintain logs of site usage in order to evaluate our visitors' interest level in areas of the website, which and how many pages they look at, how long they stay on the site, and what Web browsers are used. This data is tracked in aggregate form, not at an individual user level, and is not uniquely identifying. The aggregate level data may be shared with 3rd parties and the public. 

Cautions  
Please note, if you do not logout once registered for services that require registration, your personal information could be viewed by other users with access to your computer.

Please note, if you choose to participate in our online discussion forums, your posts will be publicly accessible, as will the username and email address you use.

Specific Privacy Issues for PrincetonReview.com

Registration:   
When registering on PrincetonReview.com you will need to provide an email address and password. You need to choose a secret password to keep the personal information you entered on PrincetonReview.com private. In addition, we request your mailing address and other information for certain services so that we can send you the information you request via mail, or in the event you opt-in, provide third party access to you.

If a user elects to use our system to inform a friend or parent/guardian about our site, particularly the Word du Jour feature or Lender's Center, we ask them for the friend's name and email address. The Princeton Review will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site. The Princeton Review stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email. The friend may contact The Princeton Review at [webmaster@review.com](mailto:webmaster@review.com) to request the removal of this information from our database.

Changing Personal Information  
You may unsubscribe to Word du Jour simply by going to the WDJ subscription page and updating your subscription (if you are not logged in, you will be prompted to log in first). 

If you want to change any of the personal information that you completed when you registered or opt-out of any of the opt-ins that you selected, sign-in to your personal My Review and click "Account Profile". 

Online Requests for Products, Services, and Information  
We provide information in aggregate about users to schools and lenders: 

  * Number of users who have visited the school's or lender's page on our website 
  * Number of users who have clicked on an external link to the school's or lender's website 
  * Number of users who have sent an instant inquiry from the school's or lender's profile page 
  * Number of users who have listed the school in their favorite schools area 
  * Number of users who have opened the school's or lender's application 
  * Number of users who have submitted the school's or lender's application 

Internally, we track users who have taken the above actions on the PrincetonReview.com website. If you have opted in to be contacted by a 3rd party, then the actions above could be used by us to direct targeted email to you. Our colleges, universities and lenders use a Princeton Review internal emailing system to send information that may be of interest to you, only if you have opted in. These 3rd parties do not receive personally identifiable information, like your name or email address. However, if you respond to an email from a college, university or lender, then your response will provide them with personal information about you. To opt-out of any online service on PrincetonReview.com, simply sign-in to your personal My Review and click "Account Profile" and opt-out of any service you wish.

Clear Gifs (Web Beacons/Web Bugs)  
24/7 Real Media, Inc., the company that serves our banner advertisements for PrincetonReview.com, uses a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that helps inform them about what content is active. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web user. Clear gifs are invisible on the page and very small, about the size of the period at the end of this sentence.

Clear Gifs can "work with" existing cookies on a computer if they are both from the same website or advertising company. That means, for example, that if a person visited "www.companyX.com", which uses an advertising company's clear gif, the website would read the clear gif's identifier and the advertising company's cookie ID number, to show the past online behavior for that computer. The information would then go back to the advertising company. To learn more about 24/7 Real Media's use of clear gifs, please go to: www.247realmedia.com.

In addition, we use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails, to let us know which emails have been opened by the recipients. This allows us to know how well customers respond to certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If you would like to opt-out of these emails, simply sign-in to your personal My Review and click "Account Profile" and opt-out of any service you wish.

Specific Privacy Issues for Homeroom.com:

We know that privacy is very important to you, especially where your children are concerned and we want you to know that we put children's privacy first. We make you three promises: 

  * Homeroom is in complete compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA). 
  * Parents will always have access to all the personal information we have about their children, including their work at the site. 
  * We will never share with third parties personal information that identifies any of the students, without parental authorization. 

Complete Compliance with COPPA:   
Homeroom is in complete accordance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998. For Homeroom, we work with all of our clients to ensure that COPPA rules are being followed in conjunction with the creation of student accounts. A printable consent form is built into Homeroom to help teachers secure parental consent when applicable. Parents will always have access to all personal information we have about their children, including all their child's work at the site

Parent Access to Homeroom  
Homeroom is designed to be a student-appropriate and kid-friendly site. Our site is highly interactive and designed to provide a different experience for every user. In order to make this possible, we collect the information and provide the services listed below. 

Students register by giving us their full name and gender, and they have the option of giving us their email address. They then pick a password. This information is then combined with the identifying information we have received from their school and the student's teacher, grade, and subject matter. This information is only available to us, the student, the student's school, and the parent. We use this information to provide a personalized interactive environment for each student and to give the teachers and school, district or state administrators the information necessary to track each student's progress and make effective use of Homeroom.

Each student has a unique user name, which is the student's screen name and the Students are publicly identified at the site only by their user name. 

As a service to its users, Homeroom provides Homeroom email services within our closed environment. Each of our users—students, parents, administrators, and teachers—is given ability in their Homeroom account to communicate with another Homeroom user As with all email accounts, children may disclose personal information about themselves to their Homeroom email correspondents. All users should practice safe computing, and parents should advise their children not to give out any personal information without parental consent. Schools and districts have the ability to disable the Homeroom email system.

Parents have their own Homeroom user accounts. Registration is similar to that for students, with parents providing their names, address, gender, and email. Through these accounts they can view and update information about their children, and send and receive email. 

Parents are welcome to review their children's personal information. They can also change or delete their children's optional personal information. 

NOTE: Homeroom.com reserves the right to terminate service for a student if a parent wishes to delete information that is necessary to our operations, such as First Name, Last Name, Grade, and Gender.

We do not condition a child's participation in an activity on the child's disclosure of more personal information than is reasonably necessary to participate in that activity. 

Sharing of Information: 

The privacy of individual user data for school administrators, teachers, parents, and students is always respected and protected. We will never disclose, sell, or rent personal information that identifies any of our Homeroom users without specific authorization to do so. Only the student, the teacher, the school administration, and the parent(s) have access to this information. Each school has agreed to maintain the confidentiality of this information. The Princeton Review retains the right to release aggregate performance information provided this information is not personally identifiable by district, school or individual students and teachers.

MISCELLANEOUS 

Privacy Certifications  
The Princeton Review is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. This license applies to the privacy practices for The Princeton Review website (available via www.review.com, www.embark.com, and www.PrincetonReview.com). 

TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. Because we want to demonstrate our commitment to your privacy, we have agreed to disclose our information practices and have our privacy practices for The Princeton Review website reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. By displaying the TRUSTe trustmark on The Princeton Review website, we have agreed to notify you of:   

1\. What personally identifiable information of yours or third-party personal identification is collected from you through the website 

2\. The organization collecting the information 

3\. How the information is used 

4\. With whom the information may be shared 

5\. What choices are available to you regarding collection, use, and distribution of the information 

6\. The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of information under The Princeton Review's control 

7\. How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information 

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact [privacy@review.com](mailto:privacy@review.com). If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe. TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concerns. 

Notification of Changes

If we make any material changes in our privacy practices, we will post a prominent notice on our websites notifying users of the change. In some cases where we post a notice we will also email users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.

In any case, if we are going to use your personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you. You will have a choice as to whether or not we use your information in this different manner. However, if you have opted out of all communication with The Princeton Review, or deleted/deactivated your account, then you will not be contacted, nor will your personal information be used in this new manner. 

Other Online Privacy Resources  
A number of organizations are very actively involved in educating Internet users about privacy issues and are pushing for legislation to preserve your online privacy rights. For more information about data privacy and cookies, you should check out the Electronic Frontier Foundation, the Electronic Privacy Information Center, and the Center for Democracy and Technology.

Disclaimer  
Though we make every effort to preserve your privacy, we cannot guaranty your privacy. Further, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law where we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on us or a law enforcement request.

Contact Us:

The Princeton Review   
2315 Broadway   
New York, NY 10024

The Princeton Review K-12 Services  
(includes Homeroom.com)  
160 Varick Street  
12th Floor  
New York, NY 10013

Email us at: [privacy@review.com](mailto:privacy@review.com)
